Guide to the William H. Johnson Papers
William H. Johnson Papers
1941-2005
Johnson William H. William Hugh 1932-
MC 00062
The William H. Johnson papers document Johnson's career at North Carolina State University with materials from 1941 to 2005, the bulk of which are from 1956 to 1983. Johnson conducted extensive research in tobacco curing in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering at N.C. State, and the papers are primarily comprised of his research notes and their associated sketches, drawings, and photographs. Also documented are Johnson's professional activities, including published papers and presentations at tobacco, agriculture, and engineering conferences around the country and across the world. Other material documents Johnson's involvement in numerous committees and groups, including chairing the Energy Advisory Task Force, a joint venture of N.C. State's School of Agriculture and Life Sciences and School of Forest Resources. The papers also document Johnson's correspondence with companies such as Philip Morris, Monsanto, Liggett & Myers, R.J. Reynolds, and others.
North Carolina State University Professor Emeritus William H. Johnson held various teaching positions in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering, starting as Research Instructor in 1956 and reaching the rank of Professor in 1969. He served as Assistant Director of the North Carolina Agricultural Research Service of N.C. State from 1983 to 1994, and received the rank of Professor Emeritus in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering in 1994. Johnson's major research interest was tobacco processing, and he was part of the research team that developed the bulk curing process for tobacco.
30 linear feet
46 archival boxes, 1 archival card box, 8 flat files
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of William H. Johnson, 2006 August 28 and 2006 October 19 (accession no. 2006-0094)
This collection is arranged in eight series: Research Notebooks; Departmental, University, and Other Professional Papers; Papers, Publications, and Presentations; Tobacco Bulk Curing Files; Energy Advisory Task Force Files; Tobacco Committees, Consulting, Reports, and Related Files; Tobacco Freeze-Drying Research Correspondence; and Sketches and Drawings.
North Carolina State University Professor Emeritus in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering, William H. Johnson was born in Fayetteville, North Carolina, on September 14, 1932. He received his A.S. in Engineering in 1952 from Presbyterian Junior College in Maxton, North Carolina, and went on to receive his B.S., M.S., and Ph.D. in Biological and Agricultural Engineering from North Carolina State College of Agriculture and Engineering (later North Carolina State University) in 1954, 1956, and 1961, respectively. Johnson held various teaching positions in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering at N.C. State, starting as Research Instructor from 1956 to 1961, then Assistant Professor from 1961 to 1965, Associate Professor from 1965 to 1969, and reaching the rank of Professor in 1969. He served as Assistant Director of the North Carolina Agricultural Research Service of N.C. State from 1983 to 1994, and received the rank of Professor Emeritus in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering in 1994. Johnson's major research interest was tobacco processing, and he was part of the research team that developed the bulk curing process for tobacco. He wrote and published more than seventy papers, holds twelve patents, and was active in numerous learned and professional societies, including the American Society of Agricultural Engineers, the American Association for the Advancement of Science, Phi Theta Kappa, Phi Kappa Phi, Sigma Xi, Gamma Sigma Delta, Tau Beta Pi, Sigma Pi Sigma, and Alpha Epsilon. At N.C. State, he chaired the Energy Advisory Task Force, a joint venture of the School of Agriculture and Life Sciences and School of Forest Resources
The William H. Johnson papers document Johnson's career at North Carolina State University with materials from 1941 to 2005, the bulk of which are from 1956 to 1983. Johnson conducted extensive research in tobacco curing in the Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering at N.C. State, and the papers are primarily comprised of his research notes and their associated sketches, drawings, and photographs. Also documented are Johnson's numerous writings, publications, and presentations. He wrote and published over seventy papers and gave numerous presentations at tobacco, agriculture, and engineering conferences around the country and across the world. Active professionally on and off-campus, Johnson was involved in numerous committees and groups. He chaired the Energy Advisory Task Force, a joint venture of N.C. State's School of Agriculture and Life Sciences and School of Forest Resources, and was active in professional organizations such as the American Society of Agricultural Engineers, Alpha Epsilon, Gamma Sigma Delta. The papers also document Johnson's correspondence with companies such as Philip Morris, Monsanto, Liggett & Myers, R.J. Reynolds, and others.
To view digitized materials from this collection, please visit the NCSU Libraries' Digital Collections: Rare and Unique Materials.
R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Company; American Society of Agricultural Engineers; Gamma Sigma Delta; Alpha Epsilon; Liggett & Myers Tobacco Company; Monsanto Agricultural Company; Johnson William H. William Hugh 1932-; Johnson William H. William Hugh 1932-; North Carolina State University Energy Advisory Task Force; Philip Morris USA; North Carolina State University Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering--Faculty; North Carolina State University Department of Biological and Agricultural Engineering--History; Tobacco Machinery Drawing; North Carolina Research Tobacco curing; North Carolina Research Tobacco; United States Tobacco industry; Drawings
- Research Notebooks, 1956-1983; 0 linear feet
  The William H. Johnson research notebooks series documents Johnson's tobacco research between the years of 1956 and 1983. Johnson kept meticulous, well-ordered notes on his research and experiments. The files are organized in the order in which they were received.
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1956 - "Tobacco 1956 Annual Report," (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1956 - "Tobacco Curing Research Showing Plans and Record of Tests and Photography," (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1956 - "Bulk Curing Analysis - 1956," (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1956 - "Efficiency of Moisture Removal from Tobacco," (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1956 - "Pilot Tube Measurements in Bulk Curing Chamber," (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1957, "Tobacco Curing Research Bulk Curing - Plans/Records," (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958, "Intact Bulk Curing Data Sheets," (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958, "Shredded After Yellowing Data Sheets," (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958, "Efficiency," (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958, "Miscellaneous Measurements," (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958/1959; "Conventional Curing for Bulk Comparisons Data Sheets," (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958/1959; "Weights and Government Grades," (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958/1959; "Bulk Cured Shredded Initially Data Sheets," (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958/1959; "Notes, 1958 Season," (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bulk Curing Notebook, 1958/1959; "Bulk Curing, 1959," (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Chemical and Physical Evaluation for 1956/1957 Bulk Curing Experiments,", January 1959 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bulk Curing 1960 - "Oxford Bulk Curing," (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bulk Curing 1960 - "Comments on Durham Display, 1958," (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bulk Curing 1960 - "Record of Tobacco Samples, 1958," (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bulk Curing 1960 - "Comments on Durham Display, 1959," (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bulk Curing 1960 - "Record of Tobacco Samples, 1959," (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Bulk Curing 1961 - "Lab Bulk Curing Data Sheets," (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Bulk Curing 1961 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Carbon Dioxide Liberation, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Bulk Curing 1961 - "Tests," (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 2 - July 22, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 3 - July 25, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 4 - July 28, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 4 - July 28, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 5 - August 1, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 6 - August 4, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 7 - August 8, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 8 - August 11, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 9 - August 15, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Small Chamber Test 10 - August 22, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation, "Experimental Results Curves (Greenhouse Tobacco),", undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Check List of Items,", undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 2, July 22, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 3, July 25, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 4, July 28, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 5, August 1, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 6, August 4, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 7, August 8, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 8, August 11, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 9, August 15, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation - "Large Chamber Test 10, August 22, 1960," (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - test data, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - "Respiration Quotient,", undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - "Atmospherically Controlled Curing Data - 1961," (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - "Atmospheric Curing,", undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - "Vapor Pressure Analysis,", undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Rate of Carbon Dioxide Liberation and Gas Analysis - "Gas Analysis,", 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Oxygen Depletion, I-62 - "Oxygen Depletion by Respiration for Bright Leaf Tobacco in a Closed Curing System,", 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Oxygen Depletion, I-62 - "Equipment,", undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Oxygen Depletion, I-62 - "Data,", 1962 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Oxygen Depletion, I-62 - "Analysis,", undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Oxygen Depletion, I-62 - "Results,", undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962 - "Baling Storage Experiment," (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962 - "Pressure Analysis,", undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962 - "Cell Permeability Study," (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962 - "Shredded Drying Experiment," (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962 - "Automatic Programmed Control,", 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Plans, 1962," (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - Recommendations, procedures (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Data" 1 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Analysis" 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - General Plans (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Procedure," (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Data" 2, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Analysis" 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Harvest Curing Experiment, 1962-1963 - "Multiple Compartment Bulk Curing, 1962," (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Research Studies, correspondence, etc., 1962-1965 - "Alternative Practice Evaluation, Tobacco Co-op Project," (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - Research Plans (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - Tests 1-7 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - Tests data (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - "Weight Record," (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - "Data," (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - "Analysis," (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Harvesting-Curing, 1964 - "Aging Study,", 1965 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Thermal Inactivation - "Sisler,", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Thermal Inactivation - "Hot Water,", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Thermal Inactivation - "Infrared,", 1964 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Infrared Studies, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Infrared Studies, 1963; "Conferences and Discussions," (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Chemical Evaluation I - Correspondence and Analysis, 1957-1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Chemical Evaluation I - "1961," (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Chemical Evaluation I - "1962," (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Chemical Evaluation I - "1963," (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "References,", 1941-1963 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Equipment,", undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - Notes, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Results,", 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Plans - 1966," (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Procedure,", 1966 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Data,", 1966 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Analysis,", 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Infrared Drying (Large Chamber) - "Research Proposal,", 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Extended Coloring Experiment - "Analysis, 1964," (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Extended Coloring Experiment - "Procedure,", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Extended Coloring Experiment - "Results,", undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Extended Coloring Experiment - "Analysis,", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Extended Curing, 1965 - Correspondence (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Extended Curing, 1965 - Proposal (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Extended Curing, 1965 - Curing Treatments (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Extended Curing, 1965 - Analyses (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Infrared Drying (Small Chamber) - Equipment and Procedure, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Infrared Drying (Small Chamber) - "Results,", 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Infrared Drying (Small Chamber) - "Analysis,", 1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - References (Research), 1965 and undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - Equipment & Procedure, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - "Results,", 1965 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - "Analysis,", 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - Results & Analysis, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - "A.C. Bulk Data - 1966," (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - "Other papers,", 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Program Curing, I-65, 66 - "Oxford Curing Units,", 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Drying Efficiency I - 66 - Purpose & Data, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Drying Efficiency I - 66 -"Intensity,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Drying Efficiency I - 66 -"Analysis,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time I-66 - Objectives & Intensity, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time I-66 - "Resistance" & "Color,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time I-66 - "Analysis,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - I-66 - "Procedure" & "Intensity,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - I-66 - "Resistance,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - I-66 - "Color,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - I-66 - "Analysis,", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Plans - 1966" and "Equipment," (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Curing Schedule," (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Weight Record," (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Data," (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Chlorophyll," (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Harvesting/Curing - 1966 - "Analysis," (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous 1966 - "Flowering," "Color Maturity," "Infrared," and "Browning," (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - "Effect of Leaf Flexure on Curability" and data - 1967 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Coloring I-67 - BAE 105 - "Procedure,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Coloring I-67 - BAE 105 - "Data,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Coloring I-67 - BAE 105 - "Analyses,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Post-Curing Conditioning of Bright-Leaf Tobacco in Bulk Curing Systems,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Procedure,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Weight,", 1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Curing Schedule,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Moisture Content,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Conditioning - I-67 - BAE 101 - "Analysis,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Varietal Browning - I-67 - BAE 106 - "Procedure,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Varietal Browning - I-67 - BAE 106 - "Data,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Varietal Browning - I-67 - BAE 106 - "300 Series,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Varietal Browning - II-67 - BAE 106 - "Analysis,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Varietal Browning - II-67 - BAE 106 - "Results,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - II-67 - BAE 107 - "Procedure,", 1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - II-67 - BAE 107 - "Data,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Browning Rate - II-67 - BAE 107 - "Analysis,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time - II-67 - BAE 108 - "Procedure,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time - II-67 - BAE 108 - "Data,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time - III-67 - BAE 108 - "Analysis,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - High Temperature (Infrared) Resistance x Time - III-67 - BAE 108 - "Results,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - High Temperature Treatment Information, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "Drying Strip,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Program Curing - II-67 - BAE 102, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Conditioning - I-68 - BAE III - "Curing Schedule,", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Conditioning - I-68 - BAE III - "Conditioning Schedule,", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Conditioning - I-68 - BAE III - "Weight Record During Conditioning,", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Conditioning - I-68 - BAE III - "Moisture Content,", 1968 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Conditioning - I-68 - BAE III - "Moisture Content vs. Time,", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Post-Curing Conditioning of Tobacco in a Convenient Curing System, BAE 114, 1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Freeze-Dry I-67 BAE 109, 1965-1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Convection High Temperature I-68, BAE 119, "Rapid Processing of Tobacco with Convective Energy Transfer,", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Convection High Temperature I-68, BAE 119, "Isothermal Drying Studies,", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Convection High Temperature I-68, BAE 119, "Transient Drying Studies,", 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Oxidative Browning I-68 BAE 116, "Procedure,", 1968 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Oxidative Browning I-68 BAE 116, "Analysis,", 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Oxidative Browning II-68 BAE 116, 1966-1968 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Coloring - I-68 BAE 117, "Procedure,", 1968 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Coloring - I-68 BAE 117, "Data,", 1968 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Coloring - II-68 BAE 117, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Coloring - II-68 BAE 117, "Analysis,", 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Phytotron 1968-1969, I, BAE 122, "Plans & Correspondence," (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Phytotron 1968-1969, I, BAE 122, "Research Data," (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Phytotron 1968-1969, I, BAE 122, "Analysis,", 1966-1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Polyphenol Reduction I-68 BAE 113, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Polyphenol Reduction During Curing of Virginia-Type Tobacco, BAE 113, 1968, Humidifier, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Convective Energy Transfer BAE 128, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Phytotron 1969-1970 BAE 122, 1966-1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Phytotron Study on Oxidative Browning BAE 132, 1968-1969, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 1971, Chemical Research Department, Swedish Tobacco Company (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Volatile Loss Experiment BAE 138, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - (untitled binder), harvesting data sheets, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Nozzle Tests & Construction - Misc., 1969-1973 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Nozzle Tests & Construction, "Low Speed Nozzle", 1968-1971 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Nozzle Tests & Construction, "High Speed Nozzle,", 1968 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Nozzle Tests & Construction, "Pressed Tube Nozzle,", 1968-1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Nozzle Tests & Construction, "Static Nozzle,", undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Freeze Drying I-68 BAE 118, miscellaneous, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Freeze Drying I-68 BAE 118, "Procedure,", 1968 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Freeze Drying I-68 BAE 118, "Analysis,", 1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "TC Conditioning,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "Separation,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "Freezing Time,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "Residual Freon,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "Turgor Conditioning,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - TC Rapid Freezing BAE 129, I, "Vacuum Turgoring Unit Development" & "Heat Conduction,", 1969-1970 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "Imperial,", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "American,", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "Fields,", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "Carreras of Jamaica,", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "Comodex,", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Customer Freeze-Dried Tobacco, "Gen Cigar,", 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Freeze-Drying Misc., BAE 130, "Index,", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Freeze-Drying Misc., BAE 130, 1969, BAE 120 "1968-1969," (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Freeze-Drying Misc., BAE 130, "Filling Capacity,", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Freeze-Drying Misc., BAE 130, "Enzyme Study,", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Freeze-Drying Misc., BAE 130, "Phytotron,", 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Pre-Frozen Freeze Dry, I-68, BAE 120, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Universal Freeze-Dried Tobacco, 1969-1970 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Mat Heat Transfer, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - BAE 133 Curing, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 10)